JILLIAN FETHERSTON

jillfetherston@gmail.com 7742281296 www.linkedin.com/in/jillianfet herston/ www.jillfetherston.com

Frontend Software Engineer

Mainly a frontend engineer with full stack potential, I've worked with several companies across the tech spectrum since 2015. I've worked for small marketing agencies handing larger clients, I strove to bring the phrase 'wedding tech' to the mainstream, and improved KPIs within e-commerce. I'm passionate, driven, approachable, and collaborative.

Professional Experience

Frontend Engineer III

Boxed | November 2021 - March 2023

- Worked as a backend engineer helping to write Boxed's SAAS catalog ingestion software
- Helped develop Boxed's SAAS front end beta application Spresso and was solely responsible for the creation of their Catalog and Bin Packing features
- Took ownership of Boxed's internal ads platform BAP becoming a point of knowledge for that platform
- Developed feature allowing users of BAP to duplicate existing campaigns for faster campaign creation

Frontend Engineer II

Boxed | April 2019 -November 2021

- Developed new features and pages for Boxed's internal tools platform called Foxtrot
- Wrote our own diffing software to allow us to track changes made to pages around Foxtrot
- Redesigned Foxtrot's Product Catalog page from a single taxonomy tree to a multi page experience for easier usability

Frontend Engineer I

Zola | June 2017 -April 2019

- Created hundreds of wedding website themes utilizing React and Less
- Brought new features such as a revamped guest RSVP experience to Zola users
- Worked collaboratively with Registry team to bring "unification" to Zola's web presence
- Oversaw and mentored wedding theme creation by front end contractors

Jr Frontend Engineer / Intern

Flightpath | September 2015 -April 2017

- Wrote HTML emails for Time Warner Cable's marketing platform
- Played a minor but important role on Flightpath's website redesign utilizing Umbraco as the CMS
- Worked on minor site updates for large clients such as Goya
- Helped to QA test redesign for major colostomy health organization Convatec's website redesign
- Wrote Wordpress theme for Weizmann Institute blog

Education

Certificate in Web

Development Immersive General Assembly at Flatiron, NY | May 2015 - August 2015

GA offered a 12 week bootcamp class which I completed. We focused mostly on front end technologies - Javascript, HTML, CSS, and Angular as well as some backend technologies - Mongo DB and Postgres. I used GA as a springboard to launch myself into a career change from food to tech and GA remains an incredibly positive formative experience.

Bachelors in Pastry arts and hotel restaurant management

Culinary Institute of America at Hyde Park, NY \mid September 2006 - February 2010

Trained under top french chefs learning classical french pastry arts and hotel restaurant management. Prior to my career change, I managed a french bread bakery in Hoboken NJ for several years.

Key Skills

- Javascript
- React
- Typescript
- Mongo DB

- Postgres
- Graphql
- SCSS/CSS